ASHFAQ AHMED A

ashfaqahmeddev@gmail.com

INDIA

in ASHFAQ AHMED

ASHFAQ AHMED

PROFILE

Self-motivated and enthusiastic worker with experience in different field. After graduating from university with a degree in the branch of civil engineering. I ended up working in the field for Three years and I was passionate about learning something completely new.

EDUCATION

2022 - ongoing MBA - (SYSTEM MANAGEMENT - Distance Education)

Madras University

2014 – 2018 Vaniyambadi **BACHELOR OF ENGINEERING - (CIVIL ENGINEERING)**Priyadarshini Engineering College (Anna University)

WORK HISTORY

2023 - present

TRIVONT TECHNOLOGIES

PYTHON DEVELOPER

- Developed and maintained user-facing websites using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and ReactJS.
- Collaborated closely with the back-end developers to integrate API calls into the front-end codebase.
- Created UI components with reusable codes for a better user experience.
- Learned new front-end programming languages and methodologies to perform tasks.
- Designed and developed new features and functionality for existing systems.
- Reviewed design mockups to provide feedback to designers on usability.

2019 - 2022

VARUN BUILDERS (SAIPEM INDIA PROJECTS)

DESIGN ENGINEER (2020 - 22)

- Proficient in creating 3D-printed prototypes and conducting performance tests to validate designs before production.
- Successfully managed a team of four engineers to deliver a new product from concept to production within a tight timeline.
- Attention to detail & find creative design solutions to problems
- Clearly conveyed complex technical concepts through presentations to the executive team and external stakeholders.
- Developing, Implementing and managing new process to improve quality and productivity.

CERTIFICATIONS

- Web Development Certification Course Udemy
- META Front End Development Professional Certificate Coursera (to veify click here Front End Development Ø, JS Ø, Version Control Ø
- Free Code Camp (web Development) ongoing

SKILLS

- HTML5,CSS3
- JavaScript
- Version Control (Git, Subversion)
- Bootstrap
- Front End Frame works (React Beginner)
- Basic principles of UI / UX design

ADDITIONAL SKILLS

- In-depth knowledge of social media website designs, color palettes and implementation of user interface
- Designing focus on digital products that determine how a website looks and feels for a better user interface

UNPAID EXPERIENCE(Intern)

2023 - 2023/06

Free Code Camp (Front End Development)

Learning some of the most popular front end libraries in the industry like html, css, Javascript and learning how to style quickly using bootstrap and adding logic to CSS Styles. Mentor guides us to understanding the principles and create a responsive website design its included classes of style to improve designing skills and understanding the beginners level of coding to proficient in coding

PROJECTS

- Created a personal portfolio website using html,css and bootstrap for showcasing your acheivement and skills
- Developed a website of Contact manager it will keep the track of the customers adding new customer and editing their information and deleting them when needed using React JS by reference
- Developed a calculator using Html, css, JavaScript
- Developing a resume generator using Javascript and its feautures like DOM manipulation, Dynamic Css.

LANGUAGES

• English - Good | Tamil - Good | Hindi - Beginner | Urdu - Good